drivethrutowin.com.au 2014-03-26

# Privacy Policy | McDonald's Australia

McDonald's Australia Limited and its Australian franchisees, subsidiaries and other related bodies corporate (" **McDonald's** ") understands that privacy is important and is pleased to provide information about its privacy policy. Please be assured that McDonald's uses its best efforts to protect the privacy of visitors to www.mcdonalds.com.au, any related McDonald’s website, social media page and any internal McDonald’s website or intranet (each a “ **Website** ”) and any McDonald’s mobile applications (“ **Mobile Applications** ”) and the privacy of individuals who provide personal information by any other means to McDonald's, including either physically or electronically (together, the “ **Collection Channels** ”).

This privacy policy explains our policy for dealing with an individual’s personal information that we collect via our Collection Channels. Unless given consent to do otherwise, McDonald’s will only collect and use personal information as set out below.

In addition to the provisions of this privacy policy, there may also be specific and additional privacy and consent provisions that apply in certain circumstances, as may be stated on a Website or as otherwise advised through a Collection Channel. Because those specific and additional provisions also relate to your privacy protection, we recommend that you review them wherever they appear. In the event of any inconsistency between the provisions of this privacy policy and those other specific and additional provisions, the specific and additional provisions will prevail.

Personal information means information which identifies you as an individual or which renders you reasonably identifiable. Your first and last name, date of birth, gender, home address, contact telephone number, mobile telephone number, email address and employment details are examples of information which may constitute personal information. Personal information may also include information we may collect about your individual preferences.

### Kinds of personal information that McDonald’s collects and holds

Personal information that may be requested includes:

a. contact information such as your first and last name, date of birth, contact telephone number, current and valid email address and home address;

b. information concerning your employment with McDonald’s, McDonald’s franchisees, subsidiaries and other related bodies corporate;

c. information regarding your interests, experience with our services and more detailed contact preferences. This information is requested in order to tailor our subsequent communications to you and continuously improve our products and services;

d. the contact details of third parties. If you are asked to provide details about other people, please ensure that these individuals are happy for their details to be given to McDonald’s and used for the purposes set out in this privacy policy (which may include using their details for marketing purposes).

**Sensitive information**

McDonald’s will only collect sensitive information with your consent. Where you provide us with sensitive information (such as information about your health) via any means, we will only use this information to serve your particular needs.

### How McDonald’s collects and holds personal information 

McDonald’s will only collect sensitive information with your consent. Where you provide us with sensitive information (such as information about your health) via any means, we will only use this information to serve your particular needs.

**Active information collection**

Personal information may be collected via our Collection Channels when you:

a. purchase a product or make a booking through a Website or Mobile Application;

b. participate in any offers, marketing activities and/or promotional activities;

c. contact us directly via any medium including SMS (Short Message Service), MMS (Multimedia Message Service), IM (Instant Messaging) and email (“Electronic Messages”), social media platforms, mail and telephone;

d. interact with a Website or Mobile Application for a specific purpose; e. browse a Website or Mobile Application generally; and f. sign-up to, or register an account via, any Collection Channel.

**Passive information collection  **

As you navigate through our Websites and access our Mobile Applications, certain information can be passively collected (that is, gathered without your actively providing the information) using various technologies, such as cookies, Internet tags or web beacons, and navigational data collection (log files, server logs, and clickstream data). For example, we may collect information about matters including but not limited to the date, time and duration of visits and which pages of a Website are most commonly accessed. This information is generally not linked to the identity of visitors, except where a Website or Mobile Application is accessed via links in an Electronic Message we have sent or where we are able to uniquely identify the device or user accessing a Website or Mobile Application.

We may combine your anonymous or personal visitor session information or other information collected through tracking technologies with other personal information collected from you from time to time via our Collection Channels, in order to understand and measure your online experiences and to determine what products, promotions and services are likely to be of interest to you. By accessing a Website or Mobile Application via links in an email we have sent and/or by accessing a Website or Mobile Application where you have identified yourself, you consent to the collection of such information where it is personal information.

### Purposes for which McDonald’s collects, holds, uses and discloses personal information

Personal information collected will be used for the following primary purposes:

a. For the purposes for which it was collected (as advised in this privacy policy).

b. For the purposes stated in a privacy collection statement on a particular Collection Channel.

c. To maintain and improve the functionality of a Website or Mobile Application to provide better service to Website or Mobile Application visitors and users, including the compilation and analysis of statistics and trends, the provision of information to you relating to the content available on that Website or Mobile Application and any e-commerce transactions conducted via that Website or Mobile Application.

d. To fulfil obligations in respect of any sale and purchase contract and/or any other contract between you and McDonald’s.

e. To send you any technical, administrative or legal notices important to our Websites and Mobile Applications.

f. To provide you with information about your transactions (including uploading of, access to, and receipt of, content on a Website or Mobile Application and purchase transactions undertaken on a Website or Mobile Application), content, services and products.

g. To provide marketing materials, events, special offers, competitions and promotions via any medium including mail, telephone and Electronic Messages or any other form of electronic, emerging, digital or conventional communications channel.

h. To maintain our relationship with you.

i. To respond to customer enquiries.

j. To manage your employment with McDonald’s, McDonald’s franchisees, subsidiaries and other related bodies corporate and facilitate effective employment practices.

k. To obtain opinions or comments about products and/or services and to conduct other market research and development (including to record statistical data for marketing analysis).

Failure to provide personal information may result in McDonald’s being unable to provide you with certain content, employment information, upcoming promotion, event or product information and/or accept promotion entries (where applicable).

For the purposes described above, McDonald's may share personal information with our related bodies corporate, our franchisees, our suppliers and our promotional partners (“McDonald’s Family”) and other trusted third parties (and their directors, servants and agents), either in Australia or overseas countries which may include but are not limited to the United States of America, Malaysia and Singapore. Of course, any use of this information by the McDonald's Family will comply with this privacy policy.

Members of the McDonald’s Family and other trusted third parties may be engaged by McDonald's to perform a variety of functions, such as fulfilling orders, conducting market research, processing credit card payments, assisting with promotions and providing technical services for our Websites and Mobile Applications. These companies may have access to personal information if needed to perform such functions. However, these companies may only use such personal information for the purpose of performing that function and may not use it for any other purpose.

McDonald’s recognises the trust with which you provide personal information, and except as stated in this privacy policy, such information will not be used or disclosed for any other purposes without consent. However, McDonald's reserves the right to use or disclose any information, including personal information, as needed to satisfy any law, regulation or legal request, to protect the rights or property of McDonald's, any member of the McDonald's Family, or any member of the public, to protect the integrity of a Website or Mobile Application, to fulfil your requests, or to cooperate in any law enforcement investigation or an investigation on a matter of public safety.

### Contact by McDonald’s and third parties

Members of the McDonald's Family and other trusted third parties (and their directors, servants and agents), either in Australia or overseas, may contact you via Electronic Messages, telephone, post or any other form of electronic, emerging, digital or conventional communications channel using the personal information provided, in respect of the primary purposes for collection of personal information as stated above.

McDonald’s does not send advertising or marketing information without obtaining prior consent, for example the consent contained within this privacy policy. If you receive any form of communication from McDonald’s which you do not wish to receive, you may remove your name from the database by utilising the functional unsubscribe facility.

Despite removing your name from the database from receiving future advertising and marketing information, McDonald’s may send you non-commercial, administrative Electronic Messages which relate to an existing user account. Non-commercial, administrative Electronic Messages may include administrative and transaction confirmations, requests and inquiries or information about a particular McDonald’s user account.

### Ability of others to view information 

McDonald’s may provide areas on a Website or Mobile Application where you can upload user-generated content, post or provide information about yourself, communicate with other users, provide reviews for content, products and/or services or interact with or vote on particular content. This information may be publically posted on a McDonald’s Website or Mobile Application and/or shared with others, including without limitation, on social media platforms and other public forums in which you choose to participate. This information may become publically available and may be read, collected and used by others outside of a McDonald’s Website or Mobile Application. McDonald’s is not responsible for the conduct of others who may read, collect and use this information.

### Children

McDonald's is very sensitive to privacy issues. We are proud of our long-time commitment to our customers. Personal information will not be collected by any person who is known by McDonald's to be under the age of eighteen (18) without the consent of a parent or legal guardian.

We urge parents to regularly monitor and supervise their children's on-line activities.

### Security of personal information 

McDonald’s will endeavour to take all reasonable steps to keep secure any personal information recorded, and to keep this information complete, accurate and up to date. The information is stored on secure servers that are protected in controlled facilities.

### Disclosure of personal information to overseas recipients

In some cases, McDonald’s may disclose your personal information to overseas recipients, including but not limited to recipients in the United States of America, Malaysia and Singapore. McDonald’s employees and data processors are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by McDonald’s. However, security of communications over the Internet cannot be guaranteed, and therefore absolute assurance that information will be secure at all times cannot be given. McDonald’s will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access to personal information.

### Access to personal information 

You are in control of any personal information you provide to us. If at any time, you would like to access, review, correct and/or delete the personal information we have about you, or if you would like to change your preferences for contacts from us, you can let us know via the contact details listed below. Please allow 30 days for this request to be processed.

Your personal information may be stored in different locations depending upon the reason for which you originally submitted the information. The more information you can provide us about when you originally submitted your personal information, the quicker McDonald's will be able to retrieve your personal information.

If requested, all reasonable steps to delete personal information will be made, except where it is required for legal reasons. Deletion of information may result in McDonald's being unable to facilitate or provide you with information about certain transactions (including the uploading of, access to, and receipt of, content on a Website or Mobile Application, and purchase transactions undertaken on a Website or Mobile Application), other content, services or product information, upcoming promotion, competition or event information, and/or provide certain content, products or services.

We are not responsible for removing your personal information from the lists of any third party who has previously been provided your information in accordance with this privacy policy.

### Links to other sites 

Our Websites or Mobile Applications may, from time to time, offer links to sites that are not operated by McDonald's which may be of interest to you. Their inclusion cannot be taken to imply any endorsement or validation by us of the content of the third party website. Linked websites are responsible for their own privacy practices. If you visit one of these linked websites, you should review their privacy and other policies. We are not responsible, nor do we accept any liability, for the policies, practices and conduct of other companies linked to any McDonald’s Website or Mobile Application.

We may use third party advertisements on our Websites and Mobile Applications. All third party advertising, if paid for, is paid for by the relevant third party advertisers. Third party advertisements are not recommendations or endorsements by McDonald’s or any of its affiliates. To the extent permitted by law, McDonald’s is not responsible for the content (including representations) of any third party advertisement on a Website or Mobile Application. Cookies may be associated with these advertisements to enable the advertiser to track the number of anonymous users responding to the campaign.

### Related McDonald's Websites or Mobile Applications

All Websites and Mobile Applications operated by McDonald's will adhere to this privacy policy. The policies on the Websites and Mobile Applications of some other members of the McDonald's Family may vary, however, because of local customs, practices or laws.

### Franchisee privacy policies 

Many McDonald's restaurants are owned and operated by franchisees, who are independent businessmen and businesswomen. Some franchisees also operate websites and are required to follow this privacy policy. If you are concerned that there may have been a breach of this privacy policy by a franchisee, please contact the relevant franchisee entity or McDonald’s restaurant directly.

### Changes to our privacy policy 

From time to time, it may be necessary for McDonald's to change this privacy policy without notice. We will post any changes to this privacy policy on our Websites and Mobile Applications. Rest assured, however, that any changes will not be retroactively applied and will not alter how we handle previously collected personal information.

### Sale of the Company

If McDonald’s merges with, or is acquired by, another company, or sells all or a portion of its assets, your personal information may be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchaser’s adviser, and may be among the assets transferred. However, personal information will always remain subject to this privacy policy.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about our privacy policy, or any problems or complaints about how we have collected, used, stored, handled and/or disclosed your personal information, please contact us at:

McDonald's Australia Limited  
McDonald's Privacy Officer   
PO Box 392   
Pennant Hills NSW 2120   
Australia

Telephone: (02) 9875 6666   
Fax: (02) 98756568   
Email: [privacy@au.mcd.com](mailto:privacy@au.mcd.com)

Please allow 14 days for this request to be processed. If you do not receive a satisfactory response from McDonald’s to your query, problem or complaint within fourteen (14) days, you may refer your query, problem or complaint to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner via the contact details listed at <http://www.oaic.gov.au/about-us/contact-us-page>.
